vhi.ie 2015-10-16

# VHI Privacy Policy

## Data Protection Statement

#### General Statement

The Vhi Group ("Vhi") fully respects your right to privacy and will only collect and process personal data about you in accordance with this Data Protection Statement and the requirements of the Data Protection Acts 1988 and 2003. For the purposes of this Data Protection Statement, "we", "our" and "us" refers to Vhi. 

#### Collection and use of personal information

Vhi, as data controller, will keep your information confidential. The information (both personal data and sensitive personal data) which is provided to Vhi by you or by third parties on your behalf (e.g. in policy applications, claims and other correspondence) will be used within the Vhi group of companies for processing your application and claims, customer services and for the administration of any healthcare related products and services of which you and any other person on your policy avail. Data may also be used for statistical analyses and the detection and prevention of fraud. 

We may share your data with trusted third parties who process data on our behalf, inside and outside of the European Economic Area. We may also share your data with other insurers to verify your cover, and with state bodies as required by law. We may also record your telephone calls for verification and training purposes. 

We will seek consent or where necessary explicit consent from you to hold, use and process personal and sensitive personal data, including up to date medical diagnoses information for the purpose of undertaking investigations into, and to adjudicate on, any claims (including the length of hospital stay and the treatment received) and for the purposes of Vhi providing information in relation to products and services aimed at managing your health and wellbeing. 

Where your policy covers people in addition to yourself, you are required to bring this Data Protection Statement to the attention of those people. Where you provide information in relation to those people you are confirming that they have read this Data Protection Statement, and that they consent to our processing of their personal data in accordance with its terms. 

Vhi collects and analyses medical diagnoses information using the International Classification of Diseases (ICD), which is a widely used standard for mortality and morbidity statistics, to assist in the development of our products and services. 

Our health and wellbeing services may include:

  * Health screenings - customers may be invited to participate in health screenings designed to help identify health risks early. 

  * Medical management programmes of care - designed to enable Vhi to actively manage the provision of healthcare services to ensure patients receive the right treatment in a cost effective way. 

  * Chronic disease management - designed to detect, prevent or postpone the onset of chronic conditions with the provision of services that aim to achieve improved health outcomes and quality of life for patients. 

#### Clinical Audit

Clinical audit is a clinically led quality improvement process that seeks to improve patient care and outcomes through the systematic review of care against explicit criteria and to act to improve care when standards are not met. 

#### Right of Access and Amendment Rights

You have the right, subject to certain exemptions, to obtain a copy of any personal data which we hold about you (for which we may charge you a small fee) and to have inaccuracies in the information corrected. If you wish to avail of any of these rights, please write to the 

**Data Protection Officer  
Vhi  
Vhi House  
20 Lower Abbey Street  
Dublin 1**

#### Direct Marketing

We will contact you as necessary about the products you currently hold with us. We may contact you about other Vhi products and services which may be of interest to you, provided you have indicated that you would like to receive such information. If you wish to change your preferences, please contact us at the above number or online here or via the MyVhi section of the Website. 

#### Data Protection Statement Changes

We may update this Data Protection Statement from time to time, the latest copy of which will always be available on our website or by calling the number above and requesting a hard copy. 

#### Contact Details

If you have any queries regarding your data, please write to the

**Data Protection Officer  
Vhi  
Vhi House  
20 Lower Abbey Street  
Dublin 1**

## Data Protection Statement for Web Users

#### General statement

The Vhi Group ("Vhi") fully respects your right to privacy and will only collect and process personal data about you in accordance with this Data Protection Statement and the requirements of the Data Protection Acts 1988 and 2003. This statement relates to the privacy practices of Vhi in connection with Vhi.ie (the "Website"). It sets out the basis on which any personal data that we collect from you, or that you supply to us, in connection with the Website will be processed by us. For the purposes of this Data Protection Statement, "we", "our" and "us" refers to Vhi.  
We are not responsible for the content or privacy practices of other websites. Any external links to other websites will be clearly identifiable as such. 

#### Collection and use of personal information

#### Healthcare Related Products and Services

Vhi, as data controller, will keep your information confidential. The information (both personal data and sensitive personal data) which is provided to Vhi by you or by third parties on your behalf (e.g. in policy applications, claims and other correspondence) will be used within the Vhi group of companies for processing your application and claims, customer services and for the administration of any healthcare related products and services of which you and any other person on your policy avail. Data may also be used for statistical analyses and the detection and prevention of fraud. 

We may share your data with trusted third parties who process data on our behalf, inside and outside of the European Economic Area. We may also share your data with other insurers to verify your cover, and with state bodies as required by law. We may also record your telephone calls for verification and training purposes. 

We will seek consent or where necessary explicit consent from you to hold, use and process personal and sensitive personal data, including up to date medical diagnoses information for the purpose of undertaking investigations into, and to adjudicate on, any claims (including the length of hospital stay and the treatment received) and for the purposes of Vhi providing information in relation to products and services aimed at managing your health and wellbeing. 

Where your policy covers people in addition to yourself, you are required to bring this Data Protection Statement to the attention of those people. Where you provide information in relation to those people you are confirming that they have read this Data Protection Statement, and that they consent to our processing of their personal data in accordance with its terms. 

Vhi collects and analyses medical diagnoses information using the International Classification of Diseases (ICD), which is a widely used standard for mortality and morbidity statistics, to assist in the development of our products and services. 

Our health and wellbeing services may include:

  * Health screenings - customers may be invited to participate in health screenings designed to help identify health risks early. 

  * Medical management programmes of care - designed to enable Vhi to actively manage the provision of healthcare services to ensure patients receive the right treatment in a cost effective way. 

  * Chronic disease management - designed to detect, prevent or postpone the onset of chronic conditions with the provision of services that aim to achieve improved health outcomes and quality of life for patients. 

#### Clinical Audit

Clinical audit is a clinically led quality improvement process that seeks to improve patient care and outcomes through the systematic review of care against explicit criteria and to act to improve care when standards are not met. 

#### MyVhi

The MyVhi area of the Website allows you to administer healthcare related products and services that we provide you, including viewing claims statements in relation to those products. In order to use the MyVhi section of the Website you must provide us with certain personal details, including your name, email, address, date of birth and policy numbers. We will process such information in order to provide you with access to the MyVhi section of the Website and otherwise in accordance with this Data Protection Statement. 

#### Other Information you provide via the Website

When you provide us with information through the Contact Us page, Ask an Expert feature, or through the Current Vacancies feature we will process that information solely for the purposes of responding to your query or processing your job application. 

#### Cookies

If you visit our site to browse, read or download we automatically collect and store information about your use of the site through certain cookies that are set. Please refer to our Cookies Policy, which is available here for further information 

#### Right of Access and Amendment Rights

You have the right, subject to certain exemptions, to obtain a copy of any personal data which we hold about you (for which we may charge you a small fee) and to have inaccuracies in the information corrected. If you wish to avail of any of these rights, please write to the 

**Data Protection Officer  
Vhi  
Vhi House  
20 Lower Abbey Street  
Dublin 1**

#### Direct Marketing

We may send you information about other products and services which may be of interest to you, provided you have indicated that you would like to receive such information. If you wish to change your preference in respect of receipt of these communications, please contact us on 1890 44 44 44 or via the MyVhi section of the Website. 

#### Data Protection Statement Changes

We may update this Data Protection Statement from time to time. By continuing to use this Website after such an update you are indicating that you consent to the processing of personal data that you provide through the Website in accordance with the updated statement. We therefore recommend that you check for updates to the Data Protection Statement before providing such personal data. 

#### Contact Details

If you have any queries regarding your data, please write to the

**Data Protection Officer  
Vhi  
Vhi House  
20 Lower Abbey Street  
Dublin 1**
